

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com

www.LondonResearchInternational.com

Mr. Logie

NATIONALITY: American, South African

SUMMARY

Mr. Logie has 22 years of experience in environmental and social management consulting. His experience covers environmental and social impact assessments and planning; environmental, safety and health management and systems; due diligence, systems auditing and contaminated site assessments. He has worked in the industrial, brown- and greenfield environments, marine and terrestrial environments. His experience covers an extensive range of industrial sectors - from pharmaceutical, automotive, pulp and paper, beverage, mining, metals processing, manufacturing to oil and gas.

He is regarded as a leading Environmental Management Advisor and has guided public listed companies on their environmental strategies and liabilities. As a recognised authority in Environmental Management he has lead multi-disciplinary teams on projects in South Africa, Angola, Botswana, Democratic Republic of Congo, Egypt, Ethiopia, Ghana, Mozambique, Namibia, Nigeria, Uganda, Tanzania, Zambia, Czech Republic, Slovak Republic, Hungary, Poland and Romania. He was the Oil & Gas Environmental Sector Lead at WorleyParsons, responsible for development of relationships and strategies within this sector in Southern and Central Africa. Notably, he was the Project Director for the Environmental Impact Assessment undertaken for the proposed hydraulicstimulation (fracking) of the offshore F-O gas field situated 120 km south of Mossel Bay.

Mr. Logie's skills include:

- Environmental & Social Impact Assessments;
- Environmental, Safety and Health Performance Assurance Audits;
- IFC Performance Standards Assessments;
- Environmental, Safety and Health Management Systems (ISO 14001 and OHSAS 18001);
- Environmental Site Assessments, Due Diligence, Risk Assessments; and
- Legal Compliance Assessments.



Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com

www.LondonResearchInternational.com

EDUCATION

- PhD (Biotechnology), Rhodes University, South Africa, 1995
- MSc (Botany), Rhodes University, South Africa, 1992
- BSc Honours (Botany), Rhodes University, South Africa 1990
- BSc (Plant Science & Biochemistry), Rhodes University, South Africa, 1989

EMPLOYMENT RECORD/PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

July 2013 – April 2014: Principal Environmental Scientist (Oil & Gas Lead)
WorleyParsons RSA (Pty) Ltd
Cape Town

 November 2011 – March 2013 : Partner Environmental Resources Management Southern Africa (Pty) Ltd
Cape Town

• 1995 – 2013 Managing Director/Owner

Biotechnology & Environmental Specialist Consultancy cc East London

Recent Key Projects include:

Project Manager ,2014

Social Baseline Assessment – Oil Exploration Area 2, Albertine Graben, Uganda, Tullow Oil

Project Manager for the Environmental Baseline Assessment undertaken for Tullow Oil and their joint venture partners, Total and CNOOC, in oil Exploration Area 2 located in Lake Albert and on the eastern shore of Lake Albert in Uganda.

• Project Director, 2014

Environmental Risk Assessment of the Land-based Transportation of Fracking Fluids, Mossel Bay, South Africa, PetroSA

Project Director for the Environmental Risk Assessment of the Land-based Transportation of fracking fluids from storage to the port in Mossel Bay.



Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com

www.LondonResearchInternational.com

Project Director ,2013/4

Environmental & Social Impact Assessment - Offshore Hydraulic Fracking of F-O Gas Field, Mossel, South Africa, PetroSA

Project Director for the Environmental & Social Impact Assessment of the Hydraulic Fracking of the F-O Gas Field 110km offshore of Mossel Bay. The scope of the impact assessment includes all land-based, port, marine traffic and sub-sea hydraulic fracking processes.

There are numerous other projects that Mr. Logie has involved – more information available upon request.

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

- Registered as a Professional Natural Scientist (Environmental Scientist) with the South African
- Council of Natural Scientific Professions (SACNASP 400102/95)
- Certified as an Environmental Assessment Practitioner by the Certification Board of Environmental
- Assessment Practitioners of South Africa (EAPSA)
- Professional Member of the South African Institute of Ecologists and Environmental Scientists (SAIE&ES)
- Member of the International Association of Impact Assessors (IAIA-SA)
- Member of the Royal Society of South Africa

PUBLICATIONS

 Mr. Logie has published three papers from his PhD in the Journal of Plant Physiology (1992-1993)

LANGUAGES

Afrikaans, English